Tiffany Han

Bay Area, CA | hantiffany@gmail.com tiffanyhan.github.io | LinkedIn | GitHub

EXPERIENCE

PARABOL | Senior Software Engineer

Jun 2020 - present | Remote

- Parabol is a highly interactive real-time multiplayer SaaS app for distributed agile teams.
 - Implemented discussion thread functionality for Check-In Meeting product. All code is open source, see PR !3884.

LYTE | BACKEND ENGINEER

Apr 2018 - Mar 2020 | San Francisco, CA

- Lead Engineer for external integrations which generated \$13M+ in revenue in 2019.
- Migrated our fulfillment monolith over to modular microservices, making our entire fulfillment system easier to debug, extend, and reason about.
- Completely overhauled our data modeling for pricing, which allowed us to programmatically calculate complex price breakdowns based on dynamic fee structures.
- Utilized our Celery servers and Redis messaging broker to implement otherwise blocking tasks as async background jobs.
- Implemented Magic Link authentication (a la Slack), which increased conversion rates and is now the default path to authenticate for all users.
- Interviewed and evaluated engineers of all levels while we 3X'ed our team from 7-20+ members in 1 year.
- Debugged everything from application code and performance issues, to race conditions between distinct processes, to server breakdowns, to unexpected system integration problems that occurred between multiple nodes.

PREFIXY | TECHNICAL COFOUNDER

Jun 2017 - Apr 2018 | Remote

- Prefixy is a highly scalable, query optimized hosted prefix search service for building autocomplete suggestions.
 - Conducted a thorough data structures and algorithms analysis to return suggestions from memory in O(1) time.
 - Utilized asynchronous, batched Redis calls in order to provide non-blocking writes.
 - Implemented multi-tenancy by utilizing JSON web tokens, Redis namespacing, and MongoDB collections.
 - Designed and implemented the system architecture which includes two Node/Express servers, Redis, MongoDB, a CLI, and a JavaScript client.

DAILY BRUIN | FULL-STACK ENGINEER

Oct 2016 - Jun 2017 | Los Angeles, CA

- Worked on bruinwalk.com, a data-driven reviews site widely used amongst UCLA students.
 - Wrote the models and views for a new textbooks feature.

UDACITY | Session Facilitator

Sep 2015 - Aug 2016 | Santa Monica, CA

- Led and facilitated weekly in-person sessions where Udacity students in the greater Los Angeles area met to learn about various web technologies together.
- Graded and provided thoughtful code reviews of student projects, providing actionable feedback on how students can improve their code.

SUMMARY

Product focused software engineer with expertise in data modeling, distributed systems, and high level architecture. Language and framework agnostic programmer. Most at home when working to take early stage startups to the next level of growth. Worked in both open offices and fully remote companies.

ACHIEVEMENTS

SPEAKING

Spoke at SFNode, 42 Silicon Valley, and Berkeley Javascript Dojo.

WRITING

Author of various technical articles, including "Building Prefixy" and "How We Built Prefixy".

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

Typescript • GraphQL • SQL • Python • Ruby

FRAMEWORKS

Express • React • Redux • Relay • Django • Rails

DATA STORES

RethinkDB • Redis • MongoDB • PostgreSQL

ETC

git • ssh • unix • vim • vscode • websockets • pub/sub

PLATORM

Docker • Kubernetes • AWS • Heroku

EDUCATION

UCLA

BA PHILOSOPHY

Los Angeles, CA Summa cum laude • GPA: 3.96 Studied analytic philosophy with an emphasis on Philosophy of Language, while devoting my time on the side to writing various programs in Python and Ruby.